<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samuel El-Borai ¤ Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://dgellow.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Samuel El-Borai ¤ Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dgellow.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam&#39;s Virtual Console</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/virtual-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/virtual-console/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m playing around with the idea of a completely virtual retro game console, in the idea of Pico8 but closer to a Commodore 64.
The project is a work in progress, I work on it from time to time when I feel like it. That gives me the opportunity to learn C++, and 6502 programming.
The project consists of: - A virtual CPU, currently an emulation of a 6502 - An assembler to parse and compile a simple ASM language to 6502 instructions - A graphical editor to be able to write programs, run them in the virtual console, and debug it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color palette extraction</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/color-palette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/color-palette/</guid>
      <description>Because I wanted to understand how that works, I created a small web application that extracts mains colors from an image file, resulting in a color palette.
The application is available online. The core is really small, it is a simple implementation of a quantizer using an histogram. The N most frequent colors are then used to compose the palette.
Source code available at https://github.com/dgellow/imgcolor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Releases (telegram bot)</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/movie-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/movie-releases/</guid>
      <description>As I wanted to play a bit with Google&amp;rsquo;s Appengine, and to do some programming with my partner in life, we created together a simple bot for the chat application Telegram. The bot, available at @MovieReleasesBot, allows people to list incoming movie releases and subscribe to them to receive a notification a few days before the actual release.
The complete code is available at https://github.com/dgellow/movie-releases. Given that this project is something we do during our weekends and that my partner doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a programming background be aware that nothing here is optimized in any way, or covered by tests, or anything that would be considered production ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Info (macOS)</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/disk-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/disk-info/</guid>
      <description>One thing I find myself constantly checking on my personal machines is the amount of free space. macOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a quick way to get that information without switching the context, that&amp;rsquo;s why I created DiskInfo.app, a truly simple application for the menu bar that displays some statistics. One click, get the job done. I use it all the time 😁. Unfortunately it isn&amp;rsquo;t available on the App Store anymore, 100€/year only for this small tool is way too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial post</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/blog/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/blog/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to organize my thoughts, ideas, and projects a bit, they are currently spread around GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab, and multiple computers and (physical) notebooks. As part of this move I created this website and blog that will be available (or already is) at dgellow.dev (newly released TLD for a fresh start!).
I plan to use it as a personal tool, a place where I can share current thoughts and ideas, easily find past ones, centralize documentation and showcase of some projects, and see my progression, learning and general improvement over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This website</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/website/</guid>
      <description>Because recursivity is funny 😃.
More seriously, I would like to improve my writing, have a place with my thoughts and projects, and see if I can keep a blog up to date. Thus this website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>