<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samuel El-Borai ¤ Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://dgellow.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Samuel El-Borai ¤ Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dgellow.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Releases (telegram bot)</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/movie-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/movie-releases/</guid>
      <description>As I wanted to play a bit with Google&amp;rsquo;s Appengine, and to do some programming with my partner in life, we created together a simple bot for the chat application Telegram. The bot, available at @MovieReleasesBot, allows people to list incoming movie releases and subscribe to them to receive a notification a few days before the actual release.
The complete code is available at https://github.com/dgellow/movie-releases. Given that this project is something we do during our weekends and that my partner doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a programming background be aware that nothing here is optimized in any way, or covered by tests, or anything that would be considered production ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial post</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/blog/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/blog/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to organize my thoughts, ideas, and projects a bit better given that they are currently spread around in GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab, and multiple computers and (physical) notebooks. As part of this move I setup this website and blog, that will be available (or already is) at www.dgellow.me (newly released TLD for a fresh start!).
I would like to use it as my personal tool, a place where I can share current thoughts and ideas, find past ones, centralize documentation and showcase of some projects, and see my progression, learning, improvement over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This website</title>
      <link>https://dgellow.dev/projects/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgellow.dev/projects/website/</guid>
      <description>Because recursivity is funny 😃.
More seriously, I would like to improve my writing, have a place with my thoughts and projects, and see if I can keep a blog up to date. Thus this website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>